Guide to the Hans Caspar Syz Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Lifwynn Foundation Files, 1912-1988, undated; Series V
  This series consists of papers which document the mission, research, and finances of the Lifwynn Foundation. It is arranged in six sections: General files; Staff files, Staff research notes; Associates' files, Correspondence and Conference notes. The files, which complement materials in the Lifwynn Foundation Records (MS 1681), reflect Syz's role in administering the foundation. They constitute a rich resource for researchers interested in the foundation's history and operation.
  The General files at the beginning of the series contain by-laws, budgets, and statements of purpose, which were issued by the staff as declarations on the foundation's mandate. The yearly budgets reveal the substantial contributions made by staff members to support the foundation. Of particular note are records specifically related to group analytic sessions, including transcripts and memoranda of group meetings, which are can be found under the heading "Staff meetings and workshops." This section also includes correspondence exchanged between the foundation offices in New York and Connecticut.
  The Staff files, which are organized alphabetically, principally document the research activities of various staff members. They contain writings, notes, proposals, clippings and some correspondence. Research notes and manuals used by the entire staff for collaborative projects can be found the end of this section. Most long-term staff members are represented in the files, though the quantity of material pertaining to different individuals varies. The files of Alfreda P. Sill and Charles B. Thompson, which document of the early group analytic meetings, will be of particular interest to researchers interested in the establishment of the foundation. The Associates' files contain similar information on scholars whom the staff consulted on a regular basis.
  The series includes a run of correspondence, which contains copies of outgoing letters written by staff members, principally Alfreda Galt in her role as secretary of the foundation. Only a few incoming letters are included in these files. Much of this correspondence is with individuals and groups exploring alternative approaches to fostering mental health. Correspondence with Gene Dawson, Michael Sperber and David Yandell, who explored the achievements of Trigant Burrow in their graduate work, would interest researchers investigating more recent appraisals of Burrow's thought.
  Conference and meeting notes include reports to the staff by individuals on their attendance at workshops and professional meetings. These are arranged chronologically.
  - General
    - Statements of purpose, 1928-1972 (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
    - "Public Relations,", 1954 (Box 59, Folder 3-4)
    - Certificate of incorporation, 1928 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - By-laws, 1930-1975 (Box 59, Folder 6-7)
    - Assets and budget, 1929-1985 (Box 59, Folder 8-10)
    - Termination of foundation, 1985 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Estate of, Aimée Guggenheimer, 1964 (Box 59, Folder 12)
      box 62, folder 91
    - Staff meetings and workshops
      - "Table notes" (transcripts of group analytic meetings), 1926-1946 (Box 59, Folder 13-15)
      - Notes on laboratory meetings, 1928-1952 (Box 59, Folder 16)
      - Observations of group meetings and interactions (H. Syz), 1951-1952 (Box 59, Folder 17-19)
      - Notes on dream workshop, 1976-1977 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Inter-office correspondence, 1933-1986 (Box 60, Folder 21-47)
    - Notes on office protocol, 1939-1959 (Box 60, Folder 48)
  - Staff files
    - General, 1936-1983 (Box 61, Folder 49)
    - Burrow, Trigant
      - Bibliographical information, Undated (Box 61, Folder 50)
      - Correspondence with Freud, Jung and D.H. Lawrence [copies], 1913-1937 (Box 61, Folder 51)
      - Correspondence with staff and associates [selective], 1927-1948 (Box 61, Folder 52)
      - Notes on mental healing (Box 61, Folder 53)
      - Writings
        - Abstracts, quotations and excerpts, 1912-1975 (Box 61, Folder 54-55)
      - Reviews and citations
        - General, Circa 1933-1963 (Box 61, Folder 56-57)
        - Journal articles, Circa 1926-1939 (Box 61, Folder 58)
        - The Biology of Human Conflict, 1939-1964 (Box 61, Folder 59)
        - The Neurosis of Man, 1949-1963 (Box 61, Folder 60)
        - Preconscious Foundations of Human Behavior, 1961-1966 (Box 61, Folder 61)
        - Science and Man's Behavior, 1954-1955 (Box 61, Folder 62)
        - A Search for Man's Sanity [selected letters], 1957-1963 (Box 61, Folder 63)
        - The Social Basis of Consciousness, 1927-1929 (Box 61, Folder 64)
      - Translations of articles [all unpublished]
        - "Neuropathologie und das innere Milieu" [trans. M. Bredow], 1933 (Box 61, Folder 65)
        - Die Morphologie der Geistesstörung [A phylogenetic study of insanity, trans. H. Syz], 1933 (Box 61, Folder 66)
        - "Die Heldenrolle" [The Heroic Role, trans H. Syz], 1933 (Box 61, Folder 67)
      - "Die Psychoanalyse in der Theorie and im Leben" [Psychoanalysis in Theory and in Life, trans. H. Syz], Undated (Box 61, Folder 68)
      - Eine Phylogenetische Untersuchung geistiger Störungen und der Ihnen zu grunde liegenden Morphologie [A Phylogenetic Study of Insanity, trans. H.Syz], 1933 (Box 61, Folder 69)
      - "La Psychoanalyse en Théorie et la Vie" [Psychoanalysis in Theory and in Life], Undated (Box 61, Folder 70)
      - Writings on Burrow [Ohtsuki, Kenji. "Merits and Demerits of Western Dichotomism. Some Comments on Trigant Burrow"], 1960 (Box 61, Folder 71)
        box 11, folder 216
    - Galt, Alfreda Sill
      - Correspondence, 1967-1971 (Box 61, Folder 72)
      - Correspondence with Foundation members, 1942-1969 (Box 61, Folder 73)
      - Notes
        - Conference, 1970-1973 (Box 61, Folder 74)
        - Personal, 1960-1970 (Box 61, Folder 75)
      - Writings
        - General, 1960-1968 (Box 61, Folder 76)
        - "An Altered Approach to Unsanity" [paper read at General Semantics conference; drafts and typescript], 1968 (Box 61, Folder 77)
        - "Therapy in the context of Trigant Burrow's Group Analysis"
          - Notes, 1963-1976 (Box 62, Folder 78)
          - Drafts and manuscripts, 1963-1973 (Box 62, Folder 79)
        - "Trigant Burrow and the Laboratory of the `I',", Undated (Box 62, Folder 80)
    - Galt, William
      - Bibliography, Undated (Box 62, Folder 81)
      - Radio Interview with Howard Whisman [transcript], 1949 (Box 62, Folder 82)
      - Writings
        - "Cooperation as a biologically basic phenomenon in animal and man; its relation to behavior disorders" [read at twenty-ninth Annual Meeting of the American Psychopathological Association], 1939-1940 (Box 62, Folder 83)
        - Phyloanalysis [notes and excerpts], 1932 (Box 62, Folder 84)
        - Phyloanalysis [draft of German translation of "Phyloanalysis"], 1933 (Box 62, Folder 85)
    - Gilden, Lloyd
      - Correspondence with W.Galt, 1951-1954 (Box 62, Folder 86)
      - Research proposals, 1967-1968 (Box 62, Folder 87-88)
      - Writings (Box 62, Folder 89-90)
    - Guggenheimer, Aimée, "Sadism Will Out" [Letter to the editor, The New Republic ], 1926 (Box 62, Folder 91)
      box 59, folder 12
    - Merker, Björn
      - Autobiography, 1981 (Box 62, Folder 92)
      - Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 62, Folder 93)
      - Visa information, 1968-1975 (Box 62, Folder 94-95)
      - Writings
        - "Buddha heart" [interpretation of Buddhist concepts], 1966-1969 (Box 62, Folder 96)
        - Short essays, Circa 1969 (Box 62, Folder 97)
        - "The nucleus reticularis thalamis: A central mechanism of attention?" [research report for 99 Eugene Sachs], 1971 (Box 62, Folder 98)
        - "Ventral thalamic function: A lesion study" [research report for Lloyd Gilden], 1971 (Box 62, Folder 99)
        - Necturus project [study of ventral thalamic function in mudpuppy] (Box 62, Folder 99)
          - Draft, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 100)
          - Correspondence concerning Necturus Project, 1967-1970 (Box 62, Folder 101)
        - "The nucleus reticularis thalami and curiosity"[research report for Eugene Sachs], 1972 (Box 62, Folder 102)
        - "The missing Renshaw cell and the structural basis for recurrent inhibition" [research report for Dr. Frumkes], 1974 (Box 62, Folder 103)
      - Why A Brain? [typescript of book, 7 chapters], Undated (Box 62, Folder 104-105)
      - Notes and essays for the Lifwynn Foundation, 1967-1972 (Box 63, Folder 106-108)
      - Miscellaneous, 1967-1978 (Box 63, Folder 109)
    - Shields, Clarence [statement on grief], 1946 (Box 63, Folder 110)
      box 13, folder 264
    - Sill, Alfreda P.
      - Notes on the early years of group analysis, 1968 (Box 63, Folder 111)
      - Reading notes, Undated (Box 63, Folder 112-114)
    - Syz, Hans C.
      - Biographical data, 1942-1984 (Box 63, Folder 115-117)
      - Comments on books and articles by Trigant Burrow, 1933-1951 (Box 63, Folder 118-123)
      - List of publications, Circa 1969 (Box 63, Folder 124)
      - Reflections on Lifwynn Foundation, 1947-1972 (Box 63, Folder 125)
      - Responses to Pugwash Questionnaire on Science and Ethics, 1959 (Box 63, Folder 126)
    - Thompson, Charles B.
      box 45, folder 83
      - Notes on early group meetings, Circa 1923-1925 (Box 62, Folder 127)
      - Reviews of Our Common Neurosis, 1953-1954 (Box 62, Folder 128)
      - Roster of Lifwynn Camp, 1923-1926 (Box 62, Folder 129)
    - Weingartner, Florence
      - Excerpts from personal notes, 1961-1963 (Box 63, Folder 130)
      - Notes on interviews with Hans Syz, 1958-1960 (Box 63, Folder 131)
  - Staff research notes
    - Scientific terminology, 1928-1956 (Box 63, Folder 132)
    - Procedure of "cotention", 1936-1980 (Box 63, Folder 133)
    - Phylotherapy, 1936-1958 (Box 63, Folder 134)
    - Research programs at Lifwynn, 1937-1977 (Box 64, Folder 135-136)
    - Study conducted at Jewish Hospital of Brooklyn [Buswell and Rheinberger], 1939 (Box 64, Folder 137)
    - Bibliographies of Lifwynn researchers, 1960, undated (Box 64, Folder 138)
    - Definitions of phylobiology as a field of research, 1946-1965 (Box 64, Folder 139)
    - Phyloanalysis, 1950-1969 (Box 64, Folder 141)
    - Descriptions of research protocol, 1960-1966 (Box 64, Folder 142)
  - Associates' Files
    - Birge, Kingsley
      - "The human condition …" [typescript], Undated (Box 64, Folder 143-144)
      - Notes by Hans Syz on manuscript, 1964-1967 (Box 64, Folder 145)
    - Bull, Nina
      - Writings and excerpts, 1941-1967 (Box 64, Folder 146)
      - Notes on Bull's writings [by staff], Circa 1956-1960 (Box 64, Folder 147)
      - Writings on Bull's Attitude Psychology by Lifwynn Foundation Staff, 1956-1963 (Box 64, Folder 148-149)
    - Gelletti, Iris
      box 47, folder 140
      - "La Neurosi dell'Uomo" [article on Trigant Burrow, reprint from Hermes, pp. 73-89, and translation by S. Capsis], 1973 (Box 64, Folder 150)
      - "Sogno, Arte, Follia" [reprint from Hermes, pp. 21-28], 1973 (Box 64, Folder 151)
      - "Conclusions" [typescript of two translations], 1969-1973 (Box 64, Folder 152)
    - Keller, Tina "Recollections of my encounter with Dr. 153 Jung" [autobiography], Undated (Box 64, Folder 153)
      box 8, folder 149-152
    - Riese, Walther
      - "Phyloanalysis (Burrow): Its Historical and Philosophical Implications" [annotated draft], 1961 (Box 64, Folder 154)
      - "The Brain of Dr. Trigant Burrow" [draft], Circa 1956 (Box 64, Folder 155)
      - Drafts of papers with comments by Hans Syz, Undated (Box 64, Folder 156)
      - Hans Syz's notes on Riese's writings, Circa 1959-1975 (Box 64, Folder 157)
      - Reviews of publications, 1950-1958 (Box 64, Folder 158)
    - Sachs, Eugene [writings with comments by Lifwynn Foundation Staff], 1967-1972 (Box 65, Folder 159-160)
    - Schelbert, Leo [essays and newsletters], 1974-1982 (Box 65, Folder 161)
    - Woollcott, Philip
      - Essays [with comments by Hans Syz], 1969-1987 (Box 65, Folder 162)
      - Review of "Of Being and of Meaning" [typescript and materials], 1981-1983 (Box 65, Folder 163)
      - "Distributed processes and the social brain", Undated (Box 65, Folder 164)
  - Correspondence
    - Bassuk, Daniel, 1969-1979 (Box 65, Folder 165)
    - Behnke, Elizabeth, 1985-1988 (Box 65, Folder 166-168)
    - Beimler, Ted, 1955-1986 (Box 65, Folder 169-170)
    - Berton, Jerry, 1964-1979 (Box 65, Folder 171-172)
    - Bhola, K., 1964-1965 (Box 65, Folder 173)
    - Birge, Kingsley and Jane [Jane Birge is sister of Alfreda Sill Galt], 1961-1987 (Box 65, Folder 174)
    - Burdett, Robert, 1967-1985 (Box 65, Folder 175)
    - Burnshaw, Stanley, 1970-1986 (Box 65, Folder 176)
    - Center for Jean Gebser Studies, 1985-1986 (Box 65, Folder 177)
    - Clarke, David, 1959-1985 (Box 65, Folder 178)
      Box 77, folder 1
    - Cooper, Stephen, 1961-1985 (Box 65, Folder 179)
    - Dawson, Gene, 1960-1972 (Box 65, Folder 180-181)
    - Dehney, Rodney, 1977-1979 (Box 66, Folder 182)
    - Galt, George and Betsy [son and daughter of Alfreda Sill and William Eagleston Galt], 1971-1978 (Box 66, Folder 183)
    - Graves, Charles, 1973-1979 (Box 66, Folder 184)
    - Guimarăes, Sidney Mendonça [Burrow's translator into Portugese], 1971-1987 (Box 66, Folder 185)
    - Hilgartner, C.A. [Andy], 1964-1967 (Box 66, Folder 187-188)
    - Karnette, Richard [Krishnamurti scholar], 1956-1968 (Box 66, Folder 189)
    - Keleman, Stanley, 1982-1987 (Box 66, Folder 190)
    - Knighton, Bob, 1970-1988 (Box 66, Folder 191-192)
    - Marburg, Galen, 1962-1973 (Box 66, Folder 193)
    - Miles, Russell, 1962-1983 (Box 66, Folder 194)
    - Panel, Kerr, Forster [financial records of Lifwynn Foundation], 1928-1985 (Box 66, Folder 195)
    - Payne, Buryl [Goddard College], 1966-1975 (Box 66, Folder 196)
    - Peace Research Institute, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 197)
      See also: Donald, Michael
    - Read, Charlotte (nee Schuchardt), 1952-1987 (Box 66, Folder 198)
    - Resource Repository and Preservation [Trigant Burrow Papers], 1974-1981 (Box 66, Folder 199)
    - Rosenbaum, Max, 1952-1988 (Box 66, Folder 200-202)
    - Shiomi, Kunio [Cotention and Zen], 1965-1987 (Box 67, Folder 203)
    - Spence, Lawrence, 1973-1984 (Box 67, Folder 204-205)
    - Sperber, Michael [assistant at Lifwynn], 1952-1988 (Box 67, Folder 206-208)
    - Stahly, Frederick [Limbic Training Systems], 1979-1987 (Box 67, Folder 209-213)
    - Ullman, Montague, 1973-1987 (Box 67, Folder 214-215)
    - White, John, 1971-1984 (Box 67, Folder 216)
    - Wikse, Jack, 1978-1988 (Box 67, Folder 217-218)
    - Yandell, David [student correspondent], 1971-1984 (Box 67, Folder 219-222)
  - Conference and Meeting Notes
    - 1912: American Psychopathological Association, Boston, May 29 (Box 68, Folder 223)
    - 1932: American Psychopathological Association, Atlantic City, June 8 (Box 68, Folder 224)
    - 1939: American Psychopathological Association, Atlantic City, June 5 (Box 68, Folder 235)
    - 1948: International Congress of Mental Hygiene, London (Box 68, Folder 226)
    - 1954
      - International Congress of Psychology, Montreal, June 7-12 (Box 68, Folder 227)
      - American Psychological Association - Workshop in Group Analysis, September 20 (Box 68, Folder 228)
    - 1955: American Psychopathological Association, June 3-4 (Box 68, Folder 229)
    - 1956
      - Workshop on Research in Group Psychotherapy, New York, January 13 (Box 68, Folder 230)
      - American Psychopathological Association, June 1-2 (Box 68, Folder 231)
      - American Association for the Advancement of Science, December 26-29 (Box 68, Folder 232)
    - 1957
      - International Congress for Group Psychotherapy, Zürich, August 28-31 (Box 68, Folder 233)
      - 2nd International Congress for Psychiatry, Zürich, September 1-7 (Box 68, Folder 234)
    - 1958
      - American Group Psychotherapy Association, New York, January 24-25 (Box 68, Folder 235)
      - American Psychopathological Association, February 21-22 (Box 68, Folder 236)
      - New York Academy of Sciences, Conference on Conceptual Problems in Psychoanalysis, March 4 & 5 (Box 68, Folder 237)
      - Association for the Advancement of Psychoanalysis, New York, September 24 (Box 68, Folder 238)
    - 1959
      - American Group Psychotherapy Association, New York, January 23-24 (Box 68, Folder 239)
      - Scientific Meeting on European Psychiatry, New York, February 18 (Box 68, Folder 240)
      - American Psychopathological Association, February 20-21 (Box 68, Folder 241)
      - American Psychiatric Association, Philadelphia, April 30 (Box 68, Folder 242)
    - 1960
      - Conference on Existential Psychiatry, New Jersey, May 8 (Box 68, Folder 243)
      - Association for the Advancement of Psychoanalysis, New York, November 5-6 (Box 68, Folder 244)
      - The Academy of Psychoanalysis: "The role of Values in the Psychoanalytic Process", New York, December 10 (Box 68, Folder 245)
      - Second Conference on Existential Psychiatry, December 11 (Box 68, Folder 246)
      - The American Association for the Advancement of Science, December 29-30 (Box 68, Folder 247)
    - 1961
      - New York Academy of Sciences, Conference on the Psychology of the Self, New York, May 11-12 (Box 68, Folder 248)
      - Third World Congress of Psychiatry, Montreal, June 4-10 (Box 68, Folder 249)
      - Sixth International Congress on Mental Health, Paris, August 30-September 5 (Box 68, Folder 250)
      - American Psychiatric Association, New York, November 10-12 (Box 68, Folder 251)
    - 1962
      - American Psychopathological Association, February 23-24 (Box 68, Folder 252)
      - First National Conference of the Congress of Scientists on Survival, New York, June 15-17 (Box 68, Folder 253)
    - 1964
      - [New Haven Report], February (Box 68, Folder 254)
      - Group-Analytic Society, London, August 31 (Box 68, Folder 255)
      - American Association for the Advancement of Science, Montreal, December 26-31 (Box 68, Folder 256)
    - 1965: American Psychopathological Association, New York, February 19-20 (Box 68, Folder 257)
    - 1966
      - New York Academy of Medicine, Thomas William Salmon Lecture by Paul D. MacLean, December 8 (Box 68, Folder 258)
      - American Academy of Psychoanalysis, December 9-10 (Box 68, Folder 259)
    - 1967
      - American Psychopathological Association, New York, February 17-18 (Box 68, Folder 260)
      - Association for the Advancement of Psychoanalysis: Karen Homey Lecture by Theodore Lidz, M.D., New York, March 30 (Box 68, Folder 261)
      - Institute of General Semantics seminar, May 6-7 (Box 68, Folder 262)
      - Workshop on Methodological Problems in the History of Psychiatry, New Haven, April 25-26 (Box 68, Folder 263)
      - Galdston meeting, May 11 (Box 68, Folder 264)
      - American Association for Humanistic Psychology, Washington, D.C., Aug, 30-31 (Box 68, Folder 265)
      - American Psychological Association, Washington, D.C., September 1-5 (Box 68, Folder 266)
      - Fairfield University Communications seminar (Box 68, Folder 267)
    - 1968
      - Lecture by Henry Margenau, February 8 (Box 68, Folder 268)
      - New York Academy of Sciences: Experimental Approaches to the Study of Emotional Behaviour, December 5, 1968 (Box 68, Folder 269)
      - American Psychopathological Association, February 16-17 (Box 68, Folder 270)
      - Association for the Advancement of Psychoanalysis. Karen Horney Lecture by Bruno Bettelheim, March 27 (Box 68, Folder 271)
    - 1969: Third Smithsonian Symposium, Washington, May 13-16 (Box 68, Folder 272)
    - 1973: Engadiner Kollegium, Zürich, May 18 (Box 68, Folder 273)
    - 1975: Conference on the Psychology of Consciousness, Boston, November 15 (Box 68, Folder 274)
    - 1979: Coevolution of Science and Spirit, New York, October 13-14 (Box 68, Folder 275)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1979 (Box 68, Folder 276)
- Ceramics Files, 1942-1990, undated; Series VI
  This series consists of Syz's files relating to his ceramics collection. They are arranged in five sections: General; Writings on ceramics; Correspondence; Dealers and active factory representatives; Museums and institutions. The first ten folders provide a detailed account of Syz's acquisition of the collection, including contacts and invoices, and materials concerning Syz's eventual disposition of it. Various reviews and writings about the collection can be found here. Syz's writings about his collection follow. Syz was particularly interested in Oriental sources for ceramic decoration and interfactory borrowing within Europe. Based largely on the pieces in his own collection, Syz published a series of scholarly articles on ceramic decorations. Reprints of these, as well as notes and correspondence relating to them, can be found here, as can reviews for and correspondence and notes concerning the production of the award-winning Catalogue of the Hans Syz Collection: Vol. I. Meissen porcelain and Hausmalerei.
  The bulk of the series is composed of files containing correspondence and other materials with a variety of individuals and institutions interested in the production, collection, or study of ceramics. This material is organized under the headings "Correspondence with individuals," "Dealer and active factory representatives files,"and "Museums and institutions." Staff of other museums wrote to Syz requesting photographs of pieces in his collection, and Syz contacted these institutions and collectors while researching his own articles. The files for the Ceramics Division of the Smithsonian Institution are particularly extensive and document the transfer of Syz's collection to its stewardship. They also provide a description of the Smithsonian's plans to exhibit the collection and include photographs from the opening night, October 29, 1966.
  - General
    - Notebook on collections and collectors, 1942-1949 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Ex-collector and acquirement invoices on the Hans Syz collection, Circa 1948-1981 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Inquiries concerning a future home for the ceramics collection, 1951-1961 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Purchase of Schulz Codex, 1978-1980, undated (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence relating to the disposition of Syz's library on ceramics, 1979 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Articles about Syz collection
      - Reviews of the Syz collection, 1947-1971 (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Gardner, Paul V., "Eighteenth Century Porcelain at the Smithsonian." (Review of Hans Syz collection, Antiques ), 1965 September (Box 69, Folder 7-8)
      - Neugass, Fritz, "Eine Sammlung alten Porzellans kommt nach Washington." (Reprint, Weltkunst World Art Review, Jun 15), 1966 (Box 69, Folder 9)
      - Miller, J. Jefferson, 18th Century English Porcelain Guide to the Collection in the National Museum of History and Technology: Works from Hans Syz Collection (reprint, Smithsonian Institution Press), 1973 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Writings on ceramics
    - Über unbekannte Malereien Adam Friedrich von Löwenfincks auf Meissner Porzellan mit Korbflechtmuster" (notes and reprint, Freunde der Schweizer Keramik, März), 1955 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - "Erratum" (typescript for Antiques ), 1959-1960 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Geburtstadressen an Dr. Ducret (typescript), Circa 1960 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Distinctive Features of Löwenfinck's Painting (notes and reprint, Antiques, June), 1960 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - "Some oriental aspects of European ceramic decoration"
      - Part I (drafts and reprint, Antiques, May), 1969 (Box 69, Folder 15)
      - Part II (drafts, corrections, reprints, Antiques ), 1969-1971 (Box 69, Folder 16)
      - Part III (reprint Antiques, Aug), 1969
        - Notes, Undated (Box 69, Folder 17-18)